ALIREZA HOJJATI

NSERC Postdoctoral Fellow

Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of British Columbia 6224 Agricultural Road, Vancouver, BC V6T 1Z1 ahojjati@phas.ubc.ca

RESEARCH INTERESTS Weak and Strong Lensing, Baryonic Physics, Dark Energy and Modified Gravity.

EMPLOYMENT 2013 - Present, Postdoctoral Fellow

Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of British Columbia, Vancouver,

Canada.

2012 - 2013, Postdoctoral Research Associate

Institute for the early universe (IEU), Seoul, South Korea.

EDUCATION

2007 - 2012, PhD., Cosmology

Department of Physics, Simon Fraser University, Burnaby, Canada.

2003 - 2006, M.Sc., Particle Physics

Department of Physics, Isfahan University of Technology, Isfahan, Iran.

1999 - 2003, BSc., Physics

Department of Physics, Isfahan University of Technology, Isfahan, Iran.

AWARDS/ HONORS

NSERC Postdoctoral Fellowship, UBC, 2014-2016.

Billy Jones Graduate Award in Physics, SFU, 2011.

Research travel award, SFU, 2010, 2011, 2012.

Graduate fellowship, SFU, 2010, 2011, 2012.

Conference scholarship, CAANDY, Denmark, 2013; CAM2011, Washington DC, 2011 (Declined); Essential Cosmology for Next Generation, Mexico, 2010; 7th Constantine High Energy Physics school, Algeria, 2004.

President research stipend, SFU, 2009.

Best seminar award, SFU, 2008.

Best graduate presentation award, SFU, 2008.

First-rank elite student by "Iranian national elites foundation", 2006.

Best M.Sc. student, Physics Department, IUT, 2006.

Top rank B.Sc. student, Physics Department, IUT, 2003.

STUDENT SUPERVISON

Co-supervision, PhD. thesis research of Yun Li, SFU, 2013-2014. Co-supervision, M.Sc. thesis research of Aaron Plahn, SFU, 2013-2014. Co-supervision, USRA research project of Starla Talbot, SFU, 2010, 2012. Co-supervision, M.Sc. thesis research of Hasmik Hayrapetian, SFU, 2011.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Lecturer: Universe and Life, 2013; Analytical Mechanics & Quantum Physics (National M.Sc. entrance exam), 2007; Undergraduate Physics (PHYS 100-level), 2006-2007.

Substitute lecturer: Special Topics, Relativity and Gravitation (PHYS 881); Advanced Mechanics (PHYS 413); Electromagnetic Theory (PHYS 821); Intermediate Mechanics (PHYS 211); Introduction to Astrophysics (PHYS-390), 2010-2013.

Certificate Program in University Teaching & Learning, 2009.

Teaching assistant: Electromagnetic Theory (PHYS 821), PHYS 100-200, 2007-2011.

Teacher: High school Physics & Mathematics, 2003-2004.

OUTREACH

Organizer, Testing Gravity 2015, Vancouver, 2015.

Organizer, SFU-UBC-TRIUMF meetings, SFU, 2012-2014.

Host, TRIUMF Saturday morning lecture series, SFU, 2012.

Laser workshop series, SFU, 2011.

Science in Action series, SFU, 2009-2011.

Starry Nights workshop series, SFU, 2009-2010. Starry Nights workshop series, SFU, 2009-2010.

Physics student association, IUT, 2000-2005.

TALKS/ S PRESENTATIONS

Strong lensing and time-delay measurements, IEU, Korea, 2013.

Lyman-alpha forest as a cosmological probe, SFU, Canada, 2012.

Cosmological Tests of General Relativity, COSMO12, Beijing, China, 2012.

Applications of Principal Component Analysis to Cosmological Tests of General Relativity, ICG, Portsmouth, UK, 2011.

Cosmological Tests of GR with Linear Growth of Structure, U. o. Manchester, UK, 2011.

 $Model-independent\ tests\ of\ linear\ growth\ of\ large\ scale\ structure,\ IAS,\ Princeton,\ USA,\ 2011.$

Entanglement theory and second law of Thermodynamics, SFU, 2010.

Detecting Features in the Dark Energy Equation of State: A Wavelet Approach, 11th Annual APS meeting, Vancouver, 2009.

Microfiber-nanowire hybrid structure for energy scavenging, SFU, 2009.

Standard Model of Cosmology and Inflationary Universe, IUT, 2004.

Model-Independent Tests of Cosmic Acceleration, Essential Cosmology for Next Generation, Puerto Vallarta, Mexico, 2011.

Detecting Features in the Dark Energy Equation of State: A Wavelet Approach, SFU, 2010.

Generation of large scale magnetic fields by coupling to curvature and dilaton field, SFU, 2008.

OTHER Copenhagen-Asia-America Network for Dark cosmologY (CAANDY) workshop, CONFERENCES/Copenhagen, Denmark, 2013. WORKSHOPS

Invited visitor, Lawrence Berkeley National Labs, Berkeley, USA, 2013.

DEUS workshop, Copenhagen, Denmark, 2011.

Frontiers of Physics in Cosmology (PiTP), IAS, Princeton, USA, 2011.

Essential Cosmology for Next Generation, Puerto Vallarta, Mexico, 2011.

Cosmological Frontiers in Fundamental Physics, Perimeter Institute, Waterloo, 2010.

TEXAS 2008, Vancouver, 2008.

PASCOS 08, Perimeter Institute, Waterloo, 2008.

PUBLICATIONS A. Hojjati & E. V. Linder,

CMB Lensing and Scale Dependent New Physics arXiv:1507.08292.

A. Hojjati, I. G. McCarthy et al,

Dissecting the thermal Sunyaev-Zeldovich-gravitational lensing cross-correlation with hydrodynamical simulations,

JCAP10(2015)047, arXiv:1412.6051.

K. Liao et al, Strong Lens Time Delay Challenge: II. Results of TDC1,

ApJ, 800, 11, arXiv:1409.1254.

A. Hojjati & E. V. Linder,

Next Generation Strong Lensing Time Delay Estimation with Gaussian Processes, Phys.Rev. D90 (2014) 123501, arXiv:1408.5143.

Y.Z. Ma, L. Van Waerbeke, G. Hinshaw, A. Hojjati & D. Scott, Probing the diffuse baryon distribution with the lensing-tSZ cross-correlation, 2015, JCAP, 09, 046, arXiv:1404.4808.

A. Hojjati, L. Pogosian, A. Silvestri & G.B. Zhao,

Observable physical modes of modified gravity,

Phys. Rev. D 89, 083505 (2014), arXiv:1312.5309.

G. Dobler, C. Fassnacht, T. Treu, P. J. Marshall, K. Liao, **A. Hojjati**, E. Linder & N. Rumbaugh, *Strong Lens Time Delay Challenge: I. Experimental Design*, ApJ, 799, 168, arXiv:1310.4830.

S. Asaba, C. Hikage, K. Koyama, G. Zhao, **A. Hojjati** & L. Pogosian, Principal Component Analysis of Modified Gravity using Weak Lensing and Peculiar Velocity Measurements, JCAP08(2013)029, arXiv:1306.2546.

A. Hojjati, E. V. Linder & Johan Samsing, New constraints on the early expansion history, Phys. Rev. Lett 111, 041301 (2013), arXiv:1304.3724.

A. Hojjati, A. G. Kim & E. V. Linder, Robust Strong Lensing Time Delay Estimation, Phys. Rev. D 87, 123512 (2013), arXiv:1304.0309.

Y. Wang, D. Wands, L. Xu, J. De-Santiago & A. Hojjati, Cosmological constraints on a decomposed Chaplygin gas, Phys. Rev. D 87, 083503 (2013), arXiv:1301.5315.

A. Hojjati,

Degeneracies in parametrized modified gravity models, JCAP01(2013)009, arXiv:1210.3903.

A. Hojjati, L. Pogosian, A. Silvestri & S. Talbot, Practical solutions for perturbed f(R) gravity, Phys. Rev. D 86, 123503 (2012), arXiv:1210.6880.

A. Hojjati, G. Zhao, L. Pogosian, A. Silvestri, R. Crittenden & K. Koyama, Cosmological tests of General Relativity: a principal component analysis, Phys. Rev. D 85, 043508 (2012), arXiv:1111.3960.

A. Hojjati, L. Pogosian & G. Zhao, Testing gravity with CAMB and CosmoMC, JCAP 1108:005, arXiv:1106.4543.

A. Hojjati, L. Pogosian & G. Zhao,

Detecting Features in the Dark Energy Equation of State: A Wavelet Approach, JCAP04(2010)007, arXiv:0912.4843v1.

A. Akhtari Zavareh, **A. Hojjati** & B. Mirza,

Generation of large scale magnetic fields by coupling to curvature and dilaton field, Prog.Theor.Phys.117:803-822 (2007) arXiv:0707.3493v1 .